噢不  查莉  宝贝  看着
Oh, no, no, no. Charlie, honey, look.
如果你每次只放上一条  就会更漂亮
If you do it one strand at a time, it's prettier.
看见了吗
See?
管他的
Whatever.
算了吧  老妈
Forget it, Mom.
叫查莉用彩带装饰就和老爸吃意面一样
Charlie with tinsel is like Dad with spaghetti.
"漂亮"是绝不可能发生的
"Pretty" just ain't gonna happen.
是吗  那你
Yeah, well, you...
这事儿没完
This isn't over.
老鲍  亲爱的  听着
Bob, honey, listen
我这个星期有许多事情要做
I've got a million things to do this week,
所以我要你帮我去带查莉看圣诞老人
so I need you to take Charlie to see Santa.
-没问题  -我刚才说了啥啊
- Sure.  - What did I just say?
我不知道
I have no idea.
亲爱的  我正忙着考虑该怎么回敬盖比呢
Honey, I'm trying to think of a good comeback for Gabe.
我再说一遍
Again,
我要你帮我去带查莉看圣诞老人
I need you to take Charlie to see Santa.
而且你一定要弄清楚她到底最想要什么礼物
And you have got to find out what present she wants most.
好的  明白了
Okay. Got it.
查莉  圣诞老人  礼物
Charlie, Santa, present.
就三个词  你就只听到这三个词
Three words? That's all you heard?
亲爱的  这比俺平时听的还多了两个呢
Honey, that's two more than I usually hear.
你们猜猜怎么着  我被纽约大学录取了
Guys, guess what? I just got into NYU!
-好啊  -噢  亲爱的  太棒了
- Hey!  - Oh, honey. That's great.
-恭喜你啊  -真酷啊
- Hey, congratulations!  - How cool.
你们在说什么啊
What are you guys talking about?
查莉宝贝儿  我知道这件事可能会让你感到难过
Charlie, honey, I know this might be sad...
但是泰迪快要上大学了
But Teddy's gonna be going away to college soon.
你的房间可以归我吗
Can I have your room?
不行  亲爱的
No, honey,
妈咪要把它改建成录音室呢
Mommy's turning it into a recording studio.
因为她是多么的伤心啊
Because she's so sad.
呃  纽约大学希望我能马上回复他们
So, uh, NYU wants an answer right away.
而如果我连去都没有去过的话
And how can I make a decision
又怎能作决定呢
until I've actually seen the place?
泰迪  亲爱的  现在可是圣诞节啊
Teddy honey, it's Christmas time
我们总不能放下所有事情来带你去纽约啊
we can't just drop everything and take you to New York.
对啊  我们可不能让你自己一个人飞越大半个美国啊
Yeah, we're not going to let you fly across country by yourself.
没有一个有空的成年人可以和她一起去  真可惜啊
Too bad there isn't another adult who can go with her.
-你是个成年人啊  -我是吗
- You're an adult.  - I am?
噢  对了  我好像是啊
Oh, yeah, I guess I am.
这样说  如果PJ与我一起去的话就行了
So I can go if PJ goes with me?
嗯  我想这应该可以
Yeah. I guess that would be okay.
不过你要帮我们看着她
But your job is to keep an eye on her.
对了  问题是  最后一场校园导览
Oh, and the thing is, the last campus tour
是在平安夜
I can book is on Christmas Eve.
等一下  慢着
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
你们俩在平安夜那天会不在家
You guys are gonna be gone on Christmas Eve?
没事的  我们会回来过圣诞节的嘛
It's okay, we'll be back for Christmas.
PJ  你在走之前帮我们做好平安夜晚餐的  对吧
PJ, you'll make us Christmas Eve dinner before you go, right?
你会帮我们做的  对吧
You'll do that for us, right?
盖比  亲爱的  别傻了
Gabe, honey, don't be ridiculous.
既然我有空做平安夜晚餐  那就不用他预先做好晚餐
Why should he make it, freeze it, thaw it, re-heat it,
然后拿去冷冻  再解冻  最后重新加热这样麻烦了
when I can just make Christmas Eve dinner?
你会帮我们煮的  对吧
You'll do that for us, right?
嗨  嗨  嗨  嗨  杰茜
Hey, hey, hey, hey, Jessie
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录 www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
Today's all burnt toast
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
Running late and Dad jokes
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
Has anybody seen my left shoe?
嗨  嗨  嗨  嗨
Hey, hey, hey, hey
■
翻译： dhui1996  CHUNTomChan  Wizard小希
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
I close my eyes, take a bite
跳上车子  放声大笑
Grab a ride, laugh out loud
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
There it is, up on the roof
嗨  嗨  嗨  嗨  杰茜
Hey, hey, hey, hey, Jessie
■
校订： Mavis  Enpistu
我的生活从此大不一样
My whole world is changing Turning around
每天都闹得天翻地覆令人抓狂
They got me going crazy Yeah, they're shaking the ground
■
后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ  liloelva
但他们相信我这个新来的姑娘
But they took a chance on the new girl in town
我不会让孩子们再次失望
And I don't want to let them down, down, down
让孩子们再次失望
Let them down, down, down
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, baby
世界有很多疯狂无奈
Things are crazy
可是我知道你会有美好将来
But I know your future's bright
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, baby
不要怀疑
There's no maybe
一切终会如你所愿
Everything turns out all right
生活有悲有喜
Sure, life is up and down
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
But trust me it comes back around
你会喜欢将来的你
You're gonna love who you turn out to be
嗨  嗨  嗨  嗨  杰茜
Hey, hey, hey, hey, Jessie
好运杰茜  纽约圣诞特辑
Good Luck Jessie: NYC Christmas
PJ  你要带我去哪里
PJ, where are we going?
我要在一小时内赶去纽约大学啊
I have to be at NYU in less than an hour.
带你去城里最著名的地标之一
To one of the most famous landmarks in the city.
我们到了
And here we are.
一辆热狗车
A hot dog cart?
这可不是一般的热狗车
Not just any hot dog cart.
是"乔治泡菜热狗"
George's Kraut Dogs.
根据网上的评论说  这里的泡菜热狗是全纽约最好的
According to online reviews, this is the best in all the city.
曾有传闻说在唐人街里有一辆热狗车跟这水平相当
There was some speculation about a cart down in Chinatown,
但后来被击垮了
but that was squashed.
是那条传闻么
The speculation?
不是  是那辆热狗车  它被公车压扁了
No, the cart. It got hit by a bus.
(注:"squashed"一词可解作击垮或压扁)
我的天呐  你一定就是乔治了
Oh, my gosh, you must be George.
我的天呐  那你一定识字了
Oh, my gosh, you must be able to read.
要两个泡菜热狗
Two kraut dogs, please.
噢  我的那个不要泡菜
Oh, I don't want kraut on mine.
那滚
Get out!
你说啥
What?
不要泡菜  我就不卖
No kraut, no sale.
你要是想要个普通热狗的话  那就去其他地方买
You want hot dog, you go somewhere else.
好吧  挺好玩的
Okay, that was fun.
我要走了
I'm gotta go.
就约定三小时后再见面吧
So, let's meet upin, like, three hours.
我要去哪里找你
Where you gonna be?
就这里  我才不会离开这里呢
Right here. I'm not going anywhere.
PJ  你有一天的时间畅游纽约
PJ, you have one day in New York City
你却要在一辆热狗车边度过这一天
and you're gonna spend it at a hot dog cart?
为啥我要离开这里啊
Why would I leave?
因为啊
Because...
好吧  回头见
Okay, see ya.
要一个多加泡菜的泡菜热狗
One kraut dog, please, extra kraut.
不行  我放多少泡菜由我说的算
No! You get as much kraut as I put on.
不许多  也不许少
No more, no less.
噢  我的天呐  真好吃
Oh, my. Mmm.
热狗外边脆口  还有泡菜的味道
The snap of the casing, the tang of the kraut.
噢  你真是个天才
Oh, you are a genius.
-而你一点也没说错  -嗯
- And you are not wrong.  - Mmm.
哈哈哈  你的名字是
Ho, ho, ho! And what is your name?
查莉
Charlie.
你是个乖女孩吗
And have you been a good girl?
呃
Eh.
你的诚实让我耳目一新呢
Your honesty is refreshing.
你想要什么圣诞礼物
What would you like for Christmas?
噢  这很好啊  好的  查莉  祝你圣诞快乐
Oh, that's good. Okay. Merry Christmas, Charlie!
呃  那么
Um, okay, so,
你跟圣诞老人要了什么礼物
what did you ask Santa for?
他是圣诞老人  他知道的
He knows. He's Santa.
呃  其实呢  他只是圣诞老人的助手之一
Um, actually, he's just one of Santa's helpers.
真正的圣诞老人是住在北极的
The real Santa is up at the North Pole.
所以呢  你可以跟我说一下你要了什么
So, you can tell me what you asked for.
这是个秘密
It's a secret.
好吧  呃  等我一下
Okay, um, hang on a second.
就站在这里  好吗
Stand right here. Okay?
呃  抱歉  圣诞老人
Uh, excuse me, Santa?
噢  听着  伙计  这个雪橇上可是有体重限制的
Oh, oh, listen, buddy, there's a weight limit on this ride.
我很抱歉  我想和刚才的那个圣诞老人说话
I'm sorry. I wanted to talk to the Santa that was just here.
他今个下午会回来
He'll be back this afternoon.
我们喜欢每隔几小时换条新裤子
We like to put on fresh pants every couple hours.
这是我第一次搭地铁
It's my first time on the subway.
这也是我第一次没拿气球
And me without a balloon.
这就是百闻不如一见的纽约幽默  对吧
There's some of that New York humor I've heard so much about.
嗯
Uh-huh.
这是我第一次来纽约
It's my first time in the city.
或按你们本地人的说法就是"大苹果城"(纽约市的别名)
Or as you natives call it, The Big Apple.
你没有书啊  杂志之类的东西看看吗
So, you don't have a book or a magazine or...
其实  你能告诉我要在哪个车站下车吗
Actually, could you tell me what stop I need to get off at?
我想去的是纽约大学
I'm trying to get to NYU.
噢  听好了
Oh. Here's what you wanna do.
搭这辆列车一直到终点站
Take this all the way to the end of the line,
然后下车  再搭上
get off, get on another train
相反方向的列车
going the opposite direction.
又是那些著名的纽约幽默吗
More of that trademark New York humor?
不  你搭错方向了
Nope. You're going the wrong way.
乔冶  现在我在这里都待上好一段时间了
You know, George, now that I've been hanging out here for a while
我有件事想问问你
I have a question.
热狗肠67%是牛肉
They are 67% beef.
我不是想问这件事啊
That wasn't the question.
那就好  我刚才是乱说的
Oh, good. I was fudging the numbers.
你每天都要在这里待上好几个小时
You're out here for hours.
那当你要上洗手间的时候该怎么办
What do you do when you have to go to the bathroom?
我的解决方法就是尽量不去想这件事
Well, I try not to think about it.
因为如果我想起它的话  那么我就要上洗手间
'Cause if I think about it then I have to go.
而现在你害我想起它了
And now I'm thinking about it!
帮我看好车子  我很快就回来
Watch the cart! I'll be back.
哇  现在这里全都是我掌管的了
Wow. It's all mine.
噢  好热
Oh, and that's hot!
呃  我要一个不要泡菜的泡菜热狗
Uh, one kraut dog, no kraut.
斯凯勒
Skyler?
PJ
PJ?
嗨
Hi.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
泰迪要去纽约大学参加校园导览  我们只会在这里待一天
Teddy's taking a tour of NYU. We're just here for the day.
你还找到工作了
And you got a job?
只是暂时的
It's just temporary.
-那么  一切还好吗  -呃  很好
- So, how are you?  - Um, great.
我刚从高中毕业
I'm graduating high school,
快要上大学了
getting ready to go off to college.
哇  你真厉害
Wow, good for you.
对了  这里是你不要泡菜的泡菜热狗
Well, uh, here's your kraut dog, no kraut.
-呃  我要付多少钱给你  -我来请客吧
- Uh, what do I owe you?  - It's on me.
这是我为我的前女友能做的最起码的事
It's the least I can do for my ex-girlfriend.
谢谢你
Thanks.
呃  很高兴见到你
Well, it was good seeing you.
嗯  我也一样
Yeah, you, too.
在世界上的大街小巷上有这么多人站在热狗车旁
Of all the hot dog stands in all the towns, in all the world...
她就是要来到我在暂时工作的这个的面前
She had to walk up to the one I'm temporarily working at.
-嗨  亲爱的  在商场里过得怎样  -一切正常
- Hey, honey. How'd it go at the Mall?  - Fine.
好吧  出什么岔子了
Okay, what went wrong?
好的  你先冷静点
Okay. Okay.
我不知道查莉想要什么圣诞礼物
I didn't find out what Charlie wanted for Christmas.
-什么  -她小声说给了圣诞老人听
- What?  - Well, she whispered it to Santa.
但之后她又不肯告诉我
And then she wouldn't tell me.
那你有没有想过问圣诞老人啊
Well, did you ever think about asking Santa?
我试过啊  但那时候
I tried to, but by then,
新裤子圣诞老人已经换成智者圣诞老人了
Wise Guy Santa had replaced Fresh Pants Santa.
亲爱的  那里疯狂极了
Honey, it's crazy down there.
好吧  跟平时一样  我又要亲自处理了
Okay, as usual, I have to handle it myself.
我去那里跟他谈谈就成了
I'm just gonna go down there and talk to him.
如果你没有带个孩子去的话  他们是不会让你跟他说话的
They won't let you talk to him unless you got a kid.
盖比
Gabe!
-什么事  -我要带你去跟圣诞老人说话
- What?  - Let's go. You're talking to Santa.
好吧  先等我刮胡子  我马上就跟来
All right. Let me just shave, I'll be right with you.
不好意思
Excuse me?
你刚才听清楚广播说什么了吗
Did you, uh, did you catch any of that?
噢  他是说  @$%$#&#%@  $%@%
Oh, yeah, he said... [Mumbling]
我就是想问那是什么意思呢
I was wondering what that meant.
本班列车将稍为延迟  不过我们将在短时间内开车
There is a temporary minor delay, but we're gonna be moving shortly.
咻  那这是个好消息
Whew! Well, that's good news.
不  这是个坏消息
No, it's bad news.
为什么啊
Why?
你不是住在纽约的  对吧
You're not from New York, are you?
对啊  你怎么知道的
No. How did you know?
因为你听不明白地铁语
'Cause you don't speak subway.
"稍为延迟"其实是说
"Temporary minor delay" means
"我们要待在这里很长一段时间了"
"we're not going anywhere for a long, long time".
而"将在短时间内开车"则是说
"Should be moving shortly" means
"我不是在开玩笑  是一段很长的时间"
"I'm not kidding. A long, long time".
为什么他们要说假话啊
But if it's not true, then why would they say that?
噢  因为他想大家冷静下来啊
Oh, because he wants everyone to remain calm.
这可不管用啊
Well, it's not working!
现在这可不妙  我要赶去纽约大学
This is not good. I need to get to NYU.
这辆列车要马上开车
This train needs to start moving...
现在啊
Now!
如果你把你的高跟鞋跟互撞三下的话
If you click your heels three times,
我肯定那家伙就会马上开车
I'm sure we'll be on our way.
喂  我现在也要赶去一个地方
Hey, I have to get somewhere, too.
我要去参加一个很重要的试镜
I have a very important audition.
对啊  但唯一的区别就是她有可能被纽约大学录取
Yeah, the difference is, she might actually get into NYU.
我想你们俩是认识的吧
I'm hoping you two know each other.
我是杰茜  而她是祖瑞  我是她的保姆
Oh. I'm Jessie, this is Zuri. I'm her nanny.
嗨  我是泰迪
I'm Teddy. Hi.
杰茜  我肚子饿了
Jessie, I'm hungry.
在我的试镜完了之后再去吃东西吧
We'll get you something to eat after my audition.
那就是说我要等你试镜失败
So I have to wait for you to blow the audition,
然后我要安慰你
then I have to console you,
最后我才能去吃东西
then I get something to eat?
对啊  与平时一模一样
Yes. Same routine as always.
可是我是现在肚子饿啊
But I'm hungry now.
而且我闻到有好吃的东西
And something smells good.
那是什么
What's that?
是千层面
Lasagna.
这是我为圣诞派对准备的
And it's for a Christmas party I'm going to.
我们可以现在开派对啊
We could have a party right now!
坐下
Sit.
呃  听着  在我们困在这里的这段期间
Um, listen, while we're stuck here,
你介意帮我练习一下台词吗
would you mind running lines with me?
没问题
Why not?
好的  我们现在身处一个高档的乡村俱乐部
Okay, so we're at a very fancy country club,
而你在和你的朋友们喝下午茶
and you're having tea with your friends.
-开始吧  -好的
- Cue me in.  - Okay.
我在南安普敦度过了我的暑假
"I've spent all my summers in Southampton.
沙滩的气息总让我回到简单朴素的生活
The smell of the beach always brings me back to a simpler time.
噢  那女孩来了
Oh, here's the girl now."
要茶么
"More tea?"
-就这一句  -对  这部分不算很重要
- That's it?  - Yeah. It's not a very big part.
从来没演过重要部分
They never are.
哈哈哈  下一个到谁
Ho, ho, ho! Who's next?
好吧
Okay,
这个我就站起来吧
let's do this one standing up.
我觉得这样最好
I think that might be best.
告诉我你的名字吧  小  伙子
Tell me your name, little... Man.
我叫盖比  我想要现金
Gabe. I want cash.
下一个
Next!
嗨  圣诞老人  我的小女儿在几个小时前来过这里
Hi, Santa. Uh, my little girl was here a few hours ago.
这是她的照片
Here's a picture of her.
呃  那是你的照片啊
Uh, actually, that's a picture of you.
噢  抱歉  让我换一张她的照片吧
Oh, sorry about that. Let me just get one of her.
是我的照片  我的  还是我的
That's me. Me, me...
噢  找到了  是一张和我合影的照片
Oh, here she is. With me.
你还记得她想要什么礼物吗
Do you remember what present she wanted?
记得  她想要个洋娃娃
Yeah. It was a doll.
-你肯定吗  -或者是一匹小马
- Are you sure?  - Or a pony.
好吧  我觉得你是在敷衍我
Okay, now I feel like you're just trying to get rid of me.
小女孩想要的总是洋娃娃或小马
It's always a doll or a pony.
偶尔也有人要小猫或者单车什么的
Once in a while you get a kitten or a bike.
但要记着  洋娃娃和小马绝对是主流
Dolls and ponies those are your mainstays.
我可不在乎这个  我只想知道她想要什么礼物
I don't care about that! I want to know what she wanted!
今天已经是平安夜  我已经没时间了
It's Christmas Eve! I'm running out of time,
我要知道啊
and I've got to know!
女士  你好像有点失控了
Ma'am, you're a little out of control.
节日的压力会令人变成这样的
The holidays can do that to people.
不  不光是过节的原因
No. It's not just the holidays.
我只想过一个完美的圣诞节  这难道有错吗
Okay. So, I want Christmas to be perfect. Is that so wrong?
乔  我们又来了个患上节日症候群的顾客了
Joe, we got another holiday stress case.
-有什么问题吗  -没错  有一个大问题
- Is there a problem? - Yes, there's a problem.
今天是平安夜  但一切都要崩裂四散了
It's Christmas Eve and everything is falling apart!
我明白你的意思了
I hear what you're saying.
现在  让我带你去拐杖糖村
Now, let's go to Candy Cane Village,
喝些蛋奶酒  然后谈谈彼此的感受
have some nog and talk about our feelings.
好的
Okay.
你说得没错  我想这样最好了
Okay. Yeah, yeah, I think that might be best.
嗨  乔治  怎么了
Hey, George. What?
你卖了个不放泡菜的泡菜热狗
You sold a dog with no kraut.
我从你的脸上就可以看出来
I can see it in your face.
我不是故意的  是卖给我前女友的
I didn't mean to. It was for my ex-girlfriend.
没有例外  每个人的热狗都要有泡菜
No exceptions! Everybody gets kraut!
除了比利·乔尔先生
Except for Mr. Billy Joel!
(注:比利·乔尔  美国著名歌手 钢琴演奏家  作曲作词家)
钢琴天才想要怎样的热狗都行
Piano Man gets it any way he wants.
我很抱歉  但当我一看见到她
I'm sorry, when I saw her,
我就意识到自己还是放不下她
I realized I hadn't really gotten over her.
-那你有告诉她吗  -没有  我迟疑没说出口
- And did you tell her this?  - No. I choked.
就这样让她再次离开了我的身边
I just let her walk out of my life again.
PJ  我觉得你应该去找她说出你的感受
Well, PJ, I think you should find her and tell her how you feel.
她听起来像是个对你很特别的姑娘
She sounds like a very special girl.
我怎么可能找到她啊
How am I going to do that?
我们现在可是身处在世界上最大的城市
We're in the middle of the biggest city in the world.
街上有一千多万人这么多  我怎能
There's got to be, like, 10 million people in the...
噢  她在那儿
Oh, there she is.
-嗨  PJ  -听着  我很高兴你回来了
- Hi, PJ.  - Look, I'm really glad you came back,
我有话要对你讲
'cause I got to tell you something.
我见到你的那一刻  我就意识到我还是疯狂地爱着你
The minute I saw you, I knew I was still crazy about you.
这也是我回来的原因
That's why I came back, too.
我刚和那边角落卖烤羊肉串的人讲完话
I just finished talking to the kebab guy around the corner...
噢  你是说埃兹拉吗  他是我的堂弟
Oh, Ezra? He's my cousin,
他是个爱情专家
and very wise in the ways of love.
他让我意识到我也还是疯狂地爱着你
He helped me realize that I'm still crazy about you, too.
-你说真的  -真的
- Really?  - Really.
现在我让你回到了我的身边  我不会再让你离开我
Now that I have you back in my life, I'm never gonna let you go.
说真的  我现在要走了
Actually, I have to go.
我和我的家人要开车到缅因州过圣诞节
My family and I are driving to Maine for Christmas.
那么就这么完了
So this is it?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
我是说  你会回到丹佛  而我就要去念大学
I mean, you'll be in Denver, and I'll be off to college.
-你要到哪里念大学  -丹佛大学
- Where are you going?  - Denver University.
你会给我写信吗
Will you write me?
每天都会写的
Oh, every day.
我来帮你们理理思路
I think I can help.
你要去丹佛念书
You're going to school in Denver?
是啊
Yeah.
而你就住在丹佛
And you live in Denver.
哦
Oh!
好吧  我等着
Yes, I'll hold.
"要茶么"
"More tea?"
你要是给我一点千层面  我就让你坐一次私人飞机
I will trade you one piece of lasagna for a ride on a private jet.
你没听错  我能办到
That's right, I can make that happen.
"要茶么"  听着就跟"油菜"似的
"More tea". See? Now it sounds like I'm saying "Morty".
嗯  您好  我今天本该在两点钟去你们学校参观的
Yes. Hi. Um, I was supposed to take the tour today at 2:00.
但是  我被困在地铁上了
But, um, I'm... I'm stuck in the subway.
等一下啊
So... Hold on.
抱歉  人家在这打一个很重要的电话呢
Excuse me, I'm sorry, but I'm trying to make an important phone call here.
是啊  我还忙着准备试镜呢  所以小点声
Yeah, and I'm practicing my audition. So keep it down.
说真的  别闹了行吗
Seriously, could you knock it off?
"要"  看见没  你弄得我把台词都忘了
"More"... yeah, see! Now
you made me forget my line!
拜托  行行好吧  这事我不说二遍
Oh, come on! Give me a break! I'm not gonna ask you again!
-你要是非得敲那个鼓的话  -所有人都给我停下
- If you hit that...  - Everyone, stop it!
我知道咱们压力都挺大的  可今晚是平安夜啊
Okay, I know we're all stressed out, but are you forgetting it's Christmas Eve?
圣诞节的意义不在于试镜或是参观大学
Christmas is not about auditions and college tours.
在于世界的祥和还有人的善举
It's about peace on Earth, good will towards men.
我觉得我想说的就是
I guess what I'm trying to say is...
把千层面给我交出来
Hand over that lasagna!
祖瑞说得对
Zuri's right.
我是什么都不会给她的
I'm not handing over anything!
我们干嘛要这样啊  现在是圣诞节啊
What are we getting so upset about? It's Christmas.
如果我没去成纽约大学  那也许就是命中注定
If I don't make it to NYU, maybe it wasn't meant to be.
是啊  也许我也命中注定拿不到那个角色
Yeah. And maybe me getting that part wasn't meant to be.
你每次都这么说
You say that every time.
这个不用让他们知道
They don't need to know that!
反正我们也被困在这了  就随遇而安吧
As long as we're stuck here, might as well make the best of it.
是啊  也许这节车厢需要的是点圣诞精神
Yeah, maybe what this car needs is a little Christmas spirit.
钢鼓哥  请吧
Mr. Steel Drum Man, if you would.
祝你圣诞快乐
<i>We wish you a Merry Christmas.</i>
<i>We wish you a Merry Christmas...</i>
还有新年快乐
<i>And a happy new year!</i>
祝你圣诞快乐
<i>We wish you a Merry Christmas.</i>
<i>We wish you a Merry Christmas...</i>
还有新年快乐
<i>And a happy new year!</i>
查莉  查莉  说出来你肯定不信
Charlie! Charlie, you won't believe it.
刚才从烟囱里来了一位特别的客人
A special visitor just came down the chimney.
你好啊
Hello-ho-ho...
查莉
Charlie.
圣诞老人  你来这做什么
Santa, what are you doing here?
是这样的  好多小孩都问我要礼物
Well, I get so many requests from kids...
有的时候我都忘了他们要的都是什么了
That sometimes I forget what they asked for.
我已经不再是500岁时那么年轻了
I'm not 500 years old anymore.
哈哈  哈
Ho... ho! Ho!
哦  圣诞老人  照着剧本演
Oh, Santa, stick to the script.
过来坐在圣诞老人的膝盖上吧
Why don't you come over here and sit on Santa's lap.
不要
No.
为什么呢
Ho, ho! Why not?
因为你是老爸
Because you're Daddy.
不是啊  哈哈  不是
No! No, ho, ho, ho.
我是圣诞老人
I'm Santa.
那你干嘛穿着我爸的鞋呢
Then why are you wearing Daddy's shoes?
好吧  小甜心  你可以走了
Okay, Sweetie. You can go now.
这下好了
Great!
现在怎么办啊
Now what?
亲爱的  放轻松
Honey, relax.
喝点儿蛋奶酒吧
Have some nog
今天就是平安夜了
It's Christmas Eve.
她今晚就要拆礼物了  咱俩还不知道她想要啥呢
She gets to open a present tonight,and we don't know what she wants!
亲爱的  放轻松  这点小事不值得咱们烦心
Honey, take it easy. It's not worth getting all upset about.
你脑子没病吧
Who are you?
那个叫乔的小精灵今天教了我许多
Joe, the Elf, he taught me a lot today.
(注:精灵=elf  自己=self)
你知道吗  没有"精灵"是拼不成"自己"的
Did you know that you can't spell "self" without "Elf"?
啥意思啊
What does that mean?
我也不知道  不过我听完这句话确实淡定多了
I don't know, but it really calmed me down.
-嗨  PJ  -嗨  在纽约大学玩得怎么样啊
- Hey, PJ.  - Hey, how was NYU?
没去上  说来话长  待会再跟你说吧
Never made it. Long story, I'll tell you later.
呃  那你呢
So, how was your day?
我吃了一大堆热狗  跟斯凯勒又在一起了
Well, I ate a bunch of hot dogs and I got back together with Skyler.
怎么回事啊
How did that happen?
我先吃了四个以后  眯了一觉  然后
Well, after the first four, I had to take a nap, then...
我说的是斯凯勒
Skyler.
对哈  一会上飞机再跟你说吧
Oh, right. I'll, tell you on the plane.
你们要是想去丹佛的话  恐怕是去不成了
If you're going to Denver, you're not going to Denver.
洛基山那边有一场大暴风雪
There's a big blizzard over The Rockies.
机场都关闭了
The airport is closed.
泰迪  怎么办啊
Teddy, what are we gonna do?
等一下  我在地铁上碰到一个姑娘  她把电话号给我了
Wait a minute. Uh, I met this girl on the subway and she gave me her number.
你好  呃  我是泰迪  您是
Hello. Hi, um, I'm Teddy, who is this?
管家
The Butler?
咱俩绝对得去一趟
We are so staying there.
我现在可以开我的特别大礼了吗
Can I open my special present now?
呃  那个  咱给查莉准备特别大礼了吗
Yeah, yeah... do, uh, do we have a special present for Charlie?
那个大号的
The big one!
哦  好吧  打开吧
Oh. Okay. Okay. Open it.
玩具屋  我就说圣诞老人知道的吧
A doll house! I told you Santa knew!
亲爱的  你是怎么知道她想要啥的
Honey, how did you know what to get her?
我还想问你同样的问题呢
I was going to ask you the same question.
-什么  要是不是你买的的话  -不是我啊
- What? If you didn't get it...  - No.
也不是我买的  那是谁啊
And I didn't get it, then who?
行了吧你俩  是我啊
Come on. It was me.
哦  我俩还以为是圣诞老人送的呢
Oh, uh, for a minute there we were thinking it was Santa.
那怎么可能
That's impossible.
地球人都知道圣诞老人得等人们睡着了才会来
Everybody knows that Santa doesn't come until we're asleep.
这么说是你用自己的钱给查莉买的玩具屋
So, you used your own money to buy Charlie a doll house?
你怎么知道的她想要什么
How did you know?
她都叨咕这事一个月了
She's only been talking about it for a month.
还有泰迪和PJ都不在家  我觉得我需要做一个
And with Teddy and PJ out of the house, I realized I needed to step up and be a...
做个好哥哥
A good big brother.
真是个圣诞奇迹啊
It's a Christmas miracle.
别这样
Ewe, stop!
放手  放手
Stop. Stop. Stop.
嗨  查莉  虽然圣诞夜全家并没有聚在一起
Hey, Charlie. Well, even though we're not all together for Christmas,
但是不得不说  在纽约呆着也挺好的
I gotta say, it's kind of cool being in New York.
-这是个神奇的地方  -也许对你来说是
- It's a pretty magical place.  - Maybe for you.
这不是拿千层面的大娘嘛
Hey, it's the lasagna lady.
-派对怎么样啊  -没去成
- How was the party?  - I didn't go.
我拿我的千层面换坐私人飞机了
I traded the lasagna for a jet ride,
结果那姑娘再没给我打过电话
and then she never called me back!
纽约真难搞啊
Tough town.
请再给我来点鱼子酱
More caviar, please.
哦  用不着这么多  你个二货
Oh, not that much, you fool.
给我放洗澡水去
And draw my bath.
-PJ  干嘛呢  -我练习呢
- PJ, what are you doing?  - Oh, I'm practicing.
我以前还从没使唤过管家呢
I've never had a Butler before.
呃  挺有意思的哈
Well, this should be interesting.
把我的拖鞋拿来
Bring me my slippers.
我知道我不住这  别跟我顶嘴
I know I don't live here, don't you talk back to me.
圣诞快乐  祝我们都好运吧  查莉
Well, Merry Christmas and wish us all good luck, Charlie.
平安夜
你猜这里面装的是个啥
What do you think is in here?
不知道啊  不过不管是什么  我猜它都快吐了
I don't know, but whatever it is, I'm guessing it's about to throw up.
是我看错了吗  还是祖瑞想占圣诞老人的便宜
Am I wrong, or is Zuri really pushing her luck with Santa?
一定要把那个挂到一个结实点的钩子上
Make sure to hang that one on a sturdy hook.
(注:圣诞老人会在不乖的小孩的袜子里装煤块)
煤块会很沉的
Coal is very heavy.
真不敢相信你居然把两个大街上碰到的陌生人请家来了
I can't believe you invited up two complete strangers from off the street.
这绝对百害而无一利
No good can come of that.
我就是这么来这的
That's how I wound up living here.
没错啊
Exactly.
今天可是圣诞夜  别这么吝啬了
Hey, it's Christmas Eve! Quit being such a Scrooge!
说说吧  你给孩子们都买了什么礼物
So, what did you get the kids for Christmas?
我哪知道  我不过是在你的礼物上写上了我的名字
I don't know. I just put my name on all the gifts you got 'em.
就因为这个  你也得帮我布置圣诞节寻宝活动
Just for that, you are gonna help me set up a Christmas treasure hunt for them.
这个我怎么往上写名字啊
How am I supposed to put my name on that?
你们好啊
Hey, guys!
你好杰茜  大家好
Hello, Jessie. Hi, everyone.
-这是我哥PJ  -嗨
- This is my brother, PJ.  - Hey.
他们几个是拉维  艾玛  卢克  欢迎光临寒舍
This is Ravi, Emma, and Luke. Welcome to our humble home.
我猜纽约话里"寒舍"就是"高耸入云的宫殿"的意思吧
I guess in New York, "humble" means "palace towering over the city".
代我父母向你们表示感谢  谢谢你们让我们在这留宿
My parents say thanks again for letting us stay here.
真抱歉打搅了你们的平安夜
We feel really bad intruding on your Christmas Eve.
这样啊  我们也不愿意让你难受啊  请吧
Aw, well, we wouldn't want you to feel bad.
别理他  他从来就没尽过地主之谊
Ignore our Butler. Hospitality is not really his thing.
真奇怪啊  你家是不是也有个不愿意做饭的厨子啊
How odd. Do you also have a Chef who hates to cook?
有啊  也是他
Yeah. Same guy.
孩子们正要开圣诞礼物呢
The kids were actually just about to open their Christmas Eve gifts.
大家都选好了吗
Has everyone picked out a present?
哇  我现在是选到了
Well, I have now.
好男人就是我  我就是卢克·罗斯
Luke Ross, trust fund recipient.
这就是你之前警告我的那个
Is he the one you warned me about?
还用说
Mmm-hmm.
(注:传说在槲寄生下接吻的情侣可以获得长久的幸福)
就因为他  我们这都挂不成槲寄生了
He's the reason we can't have mistletoe anymore.
圣诞节早上
这里到底怎么了
What in the silver bells happened here?
说吧  是谁想把我打包了
Okay, who tried to wrap me?
咦  我为什么会睡在地板上
Hey, why was I sleeping on the floor?
还有谁在钢琴里面弹钢琴呢
And who's playing the piano from the inside?
卢克
Luke?
哦  怪不得我做梦拿牙线剔牙呢
Oh! That explains why I dreamed about flossing.
咱们都希望你哪天能剔剔牙啊
We've all dreamed about you flossing.
小心点啊   小心点  小心点
Watch out, watch out, watch out, watch out.
轻点  疼啊  好了
Ow! Ow! Ow! Yeah!
咱们的圣诞树怎么了
What happened to our tree?
还有  为什么树底下就只有我  礼物呢
And why am I the only thing under it?
天啊  咱们的礼物全都不见了
OMG! All our presents are gone!
太奇怪了
That's weird.
我还从没听说过圣诞老人拿走礼物的呢
I've never heard of Santa taking away presents!
你俩是有多淘气啊
How naughty were you two?
来人啊
Guys!
还记得我昨晚打开的那套很酷的化学仪器么
Remember that cool chemistry set I opened up last night?
-不记得了  -书呆子
- No.  - Nerd.
我也不记得了
Neither do I.
但我几分钟前醒来的时候  发现了一些让我很困惑的事
But I woke up a few minutes ago, and I made some troubling discoveries.
说实话  自从昨晚泰迪和PJ来了以后的事
Actually, I don't remember anything that
我什么都不记得了
happened last night after Teddy and PJ got here.
是啊  我记得的最后一件事就是这位雀斑弟跟我调情
Yeah, the last thing I remember is freckles here hitting on me.
我记得的最后一件事则是你同意跟我约会了
And my last memory is you saying you'd go out with me.
至少也试试嘛
Worth a try.
为什么咱们都失忆了
Why can't any of us remember last night?
从我的笔记判断
Judging from my notes,
是我弄混了一种化合物  爆炸后形成了有毒的蒸汽
it appears I mixed a compound which exploded into a toxic vapor.
就是那个使我们昏迷并暂时性失忆的
That put us to sleep and caused a retroactive memory blackout.
真诚地代表我自己以及小爱迪生玩具公司向大家道歉
Sincerest apologies from myself and the Little Edison Toy Company.
呃  不是给大家添乱啊  不过有人看见我哥了吗
Okay, um, not to add another problem to the list, but has anyone seen my brother?
没有  不过你有姐姐吗
No, but do you have a sister?
它在里面  很大  很吓人
It's in there! It's big, it's scary,
我醒过来的时候  它还吃我身上的东西
and when I woke up, it was nibbling on me!
-蜥蜴吗  -管家吗
- The lizard?  - The Butler?
哇  是头驯鹿耶
Whoa, it's a reindeer!
我还以为是驼鹿呢
I thought it was a moose!
你好啊  小鹿鹿
Nice reindeer.
求你告诉我你现在是休息呢  圣诞老人就快来接你了
Please tell me you're on a break and Santa's on his way to pick you up!
没错  爸  我们圣诞节玩得很开心
Yes, Dad, we're having a great Christmas.
他们家还有头驯鹿呢
They even have a reindeer.
是啊  对  当然是塑料的
Right, uh, yeah, of course, a plastic one.
要是真的  那可就太吓人了
A real one would be bizarre and frightening.
乖  普兰瑟
Good boy, Prancer.
这家伙又咬人又踢人的
More like Biter, or Kicker.
我们到处都找过了  就是找不到咱的礼物
We looked everywhere, but we could not find any presents.
袜子都没了
Not even socks.
在这种情况下  能有个腈纶毛衫我就挺高兴了
At this point, I'd be happy with an acrylic sweater.
圣诞老人  如果你听见了的话  这话不是我真心说的
Santa, if you're listening, I didn't mean that!
好吧  咱们一定要在你们父母回家之前把这事弄清楚
Okay, we need to figure this out before your parents get home.
分成两队行动
We'll split into two teams.
男生们  你们就留在家里
Boys, you sift through the wreckage for anything that
寻找一切能让我们回忆起昨晚的事的线索
might help us remember what happened last night.
还有  我们一边找线索  一边还要清理屋子
And, as we sift, we will also dust and put away!
我真想换队
I seriously need to change teams.
PJ你负责
PJ, you're in charge.
真的吗  好耶
Really? Cool!
拉维  换你负责
Ravi, you're in charge.
真恶心  真不敢相信圣诞节的我
Ugh! I can't believe I have to clean up
还得给你清理你那傻了吧唧的化学仪器
your stupid chemistry set on Christmas.
原谚语为Stop crying over spilled milk (别在洒了的牛奶上哭泣)
覆柠檬酸镁难收
Stop crying over spilled magnesium citrate,
赶快帮忙找找昨天的事的线索吧
and help us find some clues about what happened last night!
你俩快来  我觉得找到第一条线索了
Hey guys, I think I found our first clue!
你怎么那么肯定
Why do you say that?
因为这纸上写着"第一条线索"
Because this paper says, "your first clue".
哦  我要读
Ooh! Dibs on reading it!
"欢迎参加圣诞寻宝活动"
"Welcome to your Christmas treasure hunt".
真是个奇怪的假期大礼
What a whimsical holiday treat.
"收到礼物确实好  但找礼物更美妙"
"Sure, it is fun to just get a present, but hunting for it is much more pleasant".
有人把咱们的礼物藏起来了
Someone hid our presents?
得是多变态的人能这么干啊
What kind of sicko would do that?
好了  肖恩去洗手间了
Okay, Shawn's heading for the restroom,
我们大约有五分钟的时间看昨晚的监控录像
so we've got about five minutes to check last night's security footage.
他今早吃的是皇后牌玉米卷
He had Taco Queen for breakfast.
少于二十分钟他是出不来了
We've got at least 20.
咱们得弄清楚昨晚你和PJ来了以后发生了什么
We need to figure out what happened after you and PJ got here last night.
是啊  还有是谁鸟么悄地就把这头驯鹿放上来了
Yeah, and who let a reindeer up unannounced.
你要是认识我们的看门人的话  这事就不奇怪了
If you knew our door staff, you wouldn't be surprised by that.
就盯着那个偷咱礼物的毛贼看就行了
Just keep looking for the monster who stole our presents!
好的  目前还没有出现驯鹿或是贼
Okay, no reindeer or monsters yet.
大号的小精灵啊
That's a giant Elf.
才不是精灵呢  那是我们家的管家
That's no Elf, that's our Butler!
伯特伦吗  我就说他有精灵血统的嘛
It was Bertram? I always knew he was part Grinch!
他居然偷小孩的礼物
He's stealing presents from children?
不会有人比他更卑劣了
It does not get any lower than that.
哇哦  好像他没在单独作案啊
Whoa, it looks like he didn't act alone.
杰茜
Jessie?
之前的话当我没说
Okay, forget about the lowest.
我们又没害死人
It's not like anybody died.
我们还没看全录像呢  怎么会知道
We haven't seen the rest of the tape.
是你干的
It was you?
是你偷了我们的礼物
You stole our presents?
我也不知道为什么我会
I don't know why I would...
哦  我想起来了
Oh! Now I remember!
我想给你们弄个圣诞寻宝活动  所以就把礼物都藏起来了
I wanted to give you guys a Christmas treasure hunt, so I hid all your presents.
听起来挺好玩的  对吧
Sounds fun, right?
没有直接在圣诞树下拿好玩
Not as fun as finding them under the tree!
还有穿着睡衣打开它们  假装是圣诞老人送的
And opening them in our jammies, as Santa intended!
好了  孩子们  放轻松
Okay, guys, relax.
咱们去把礼物拿回来不就完事了么
We'll just go get the presents.
行啊  礼物都在哪呢
Great, where are they?
我也不知道啊
I have no idea.
你可是越过我的底线了
Oh, someone's about to get Jack Frosted up!
你干嘛不把礼物藏在公寓里啊
Why didn't you just hide them in the apartment?
是啊  那样的话可比这明智多了
Yeah, that would have been smarter.
好吧  谁请她来的
Okay, who invited her?
让我去抓她啊
Let me at her!
祖瑞  你不是昨天还在地铁上
Zuri, aren't you the same girl who was just on the subway yesterday
主张世界和平吗
preaching peace on Earth?
我只知道  我没拿到我的礼物
All I know is, I don't have my presents,
所以我要拆开点儿什么东西
so I need something to rip open!
好吧  大家冷静点
Okay, guys, calm down!
我们来把口袋和包包掏空
Let's just empty our pockets and purses
看看能找到什么让我回忆起来什么的东西
and see if anything jogs my memory.
没有
Nope.
我只有我紧急备用的珠宝
All I have is my emergency change of jewelry.
我只有随身带的零花钱
All I've got is my walking around cash.
嗯  我没啥东西
Well, um, I've got nothing,
但我自愿去查一下你的沙发垫
but dibs on checking your couch cushions!
好吧  一团棉绒  桉树油全身护理的收据
Okay, ball of lint, certificate for a full-body eucalyptus wrap,
还有在中央公园租柜子时的发票
and a receipt for a locker rental in Central Park.
我几个月前就给你那收据了
I gave you that certificate months ago!
你真是个不领情的小偷
You're a thief and ungrateful!
我没去花五个小时就为闻起来像考拉的点心
Well, excuse me for not wanting to spend five hours
实在是不好意思啊
just to smell like a koala snack!
等一下  这发票上写的日期是12月24日
Wait, this receipt is dated December 24th.
是溜冰场里的339号柜子
For locker number 339 at the skating rink.
也许我把礼物放在那儿了
Maybe I put the presents in there!
那我们还楞在这儿干嘛啊  赶快走呀
Then what are we doing here? Let's go!
呃  各位  咱们就不带这头驯鹿了  对吧
Um, guys, uh, we're not taking the reindeer with us, right?
当然不会啦  那会很傻的
Of course not, that would be silly.
肖恩  你介意帮忙看着我们的狗狗吗
Sean, would you mind watching our dog?
再见啦  小斑
Bye, Spot.
我觉得他信了
I think he bought it.
哦  第十二个线索在这儿
Oh, there is the 12th clue!
好嘞
All right.
"光荣一关等到你
"Now you have come to the glorious stage,
答案在爬虫笼里"
where the answer is found in the reptile's cage."
哦  爬行动物  这简单啊
Oh, reptile! This one's easy.
等等  吉普林夫人不喜欢陌生人在它
Wait! Mrs. Kipling does not like strangers in her...
笼子里
...cage.
我找  我找到了
I got... I got it!
呼  哇  这公寓里野生动物还是出乎意料的多嘛
Whew! Wow, there's a lot of unexpected wildlife in this apartment.
好吧  最后一条线索
Okay, final clue.
"别着急  停下想想
"Don't rush off, stop and think.
礼物就在溜冰场”
Your presents are in a box by the rink."
肯定指的是中央公园的溜冰场
It must mean the ice skating rink in Central Park.
对  拉维  你太有才了  咱走吧
Yes! Ravi, you're brilliant! Let's go!
哦  呃  在去的路上
Oh! Uh, on the way,
我们能停下去买点儿止血带和半升O型阴性血啊
can we stop and pick up a tourniquet and a pint of O-negative?
就在这儿了  339号柜子
Here it is! Locker 339!
好吧  我这儿有密码
Okay, I have the combination.
"请付款两毛五"  有人有两毛五吗
"Balance due 25 cents?" Does anyone have a quarter?
来  我有两毛五
Here, I have one.
好
Okay...
伯特伦
Bertram!
你在这里干啥呀
What are you doing in there?
试着不让胳膊肘碰到胆囊啊
Trying to keep my elbow out of my gall bladder!
杰茜  昨晚你应该回来接我的
Jessie, last night, you were supposed to come right back for me!
-你为什么没回来啊  -呃  我毫无头绪
- Why didn't you?  - Uh, I have no idea!
我们几个都不记得昨晚发生啥事儿了
None of us have any memory of last night.
肯定很棒吧
Must be nice!
我整晚都被挤在这臭柜子里
I spent the entire night wedged inside this stinky locker!
我再也去不成健身房了
I'll never be able to go to the gym again.
"再也"
Again?
你别先起哄
Don't you even start!
等等  你为啥会困在那里
Wait, why are you trapped in there?
噢  圣诞老人是不是让你一边罚站去啦
Aw, did Santa give you a time-out?
杰茜  这都是你的错
Jessie, this is all your fault.
在我们离开时  孩子们还睡着正香呢
The kids were asleep when we left,
平安夜
所以我不懂为什么我们要穿这些特搞的戏服呢
so I don't understand why we had to wear these stupid costumes.
我只想看看你穿上这个是啥效果
I just wanted to see if you'd actually put it on.
明年的圣诞贺卡搞定了
Now I have next year's Christmas card!
来  我们回家吧
Come on, let's go home.
啊哦  是祖瑞  她不呆在床上来这儿干嘛
Uh-oh, it's Zuri! What is she doing not in bed?
为什么不问下她保姆呢
Why don't you ask her nanny?
哦  对呀
Oh, right.
快藏起来啊  我不想把圣诞惊喜泄露出去啊
Just hide! I don't want my Christmas surprise to get spoiled.
-躲进哪里   -这里面  进去啊
- Where?  - In there! There! There, there! Go.
进去啊
Go, go, go!
来啊  再进去点儿啊
Come on, move farther back!
不行啊  你以为后面是啥啊  纳尼亚王国吗
I can't! What do you think is back here, Narnia?
杰茜和伯特伦肯定就在这附近
I know Jessie and Bertram are here somewhere.
我看到他们带着礼物溜出来了
I saw them sneak out with all the presents!
好吧  我们在外面溜达够久了吧
Okay, we've been wandering around so long,
我连每只老鼠都认得出来了
I am starting to recognize all the rats.
咱就不能回家吗
Can we please go back home?
嘿  我不知道你在那无名小镇里是咋处理事情的
Hey, I don't know how you roll in that Podunk hill town,
但在纽约  我们就要拿回应得的东西
but here in New York, we get what's ours.
好吧  丹佛才不是什么无名小镇呢
Okay, Denver is not a Podunk hill town.
我们有专业的橄榄球队  还有我们自己的煎蛋卷
We have a pro football team, and our own omelet!
(注:JAY Z是嘻哈音乐歌手)
等到你们有俩橄榄球队和JAY Z时  你再打给我吧
Call me when you have two football teams, and Jay-Z.
好了  伯特伦  她们走了  你可以出来了
All right, Bertram, they're all gone, you can come out now.
啊哦
Uh-oh.
你这"啊哦"是什么意思
What does "uh-oh" mean?
这柜子是自动锁上的  我需要两毛五把你放出来
It locked automatically, and I need a quarter to get you out!
来啊  拿钱过来啊  我会还给你的
Go ahead, splurge. I'll pay you back.
我没两毛五啊
I don't have a quarter!
好吧  我回家去拿  去去就来
Okay, I'll run home to get one, and be right back.
放轻松点儿  就从这里呼吸吧
Just try to relax, and breathe through this.
哦  谢了
Oh, thanks.
哦  等等  你从哪儿拿的这根吸管
Oh, wait, where did you get this straw?
垃圾桶里
From the trash.
然后你就没回来过了
Then you never came back!
圣诞节早上
我就在这儿跟个发霉的香肠三明治一起待着
I was stuck in here with a moldy salami sandwich!
我没看见三明治啊
I don't see a sandwich.
别找我茬啊  你没像我这样混过
Don't judge me! You didn't live through what I did!
好  礼物在其中一个柜子里
Okay, the presents are in one of these lockers!
我们知道  大侦探
We know, Sherlock.
哦  你好啊  伯特伦  圣诞快乐
Oh, hello, Bertram. Merry Christmas.
噢  你肯定是跟着我的圣诞寻宝线索跟过来了
Aw, you must have followed my Christmas treasure hunt!
确实是  这真是令人愉快  轻而易举啊
Indeed we did, and what a delightful romp it was!
令人愉快
Delightful?
我就快被个巨龙吃了
I was almost eaten by a dragon!
而且这些礼物根本没我的份儿
And the presents aren't even for me!
我爸每次都把我的圣诞礼物藏起来
My dad always hid my Christmas presents.
他说过  "你不能不劳而获"
He said, "You never get anything in life without working for it."
礼物除外啊  不然为啥叫礼物啊
Except presents! That's the whole point!
知道吗  其实我觉得圣诞寻宝很有创新啊
You know, I actually think a Christmas treasure hunt is very inventive.
谢谢  泰迪
Thank you, Teddy.
你是从科罗拉多州来的  电力你都觉得很新奇
You're from Colorado. You think electricity is inventive.
祖瑞  我们去年去科罗拉多州滑雪时你很喜欢那里啊
Zuri! You loved Colorado when we went skiing there last year.
哦  那是科罗拉多州
Oh, that was Colorado?
我还以为那是瑞士呢
I thought that was Switzerland.
嗯  从我角度上讲  坐私人飞机想不睡着都难
Well, in my defense, it's very easy to fall asleep on a private jet.
你真是个非常烦人的小姑娘
You're a very annoying little girl.
伯特伦  礼物在哪个柜子里
Bertram, which locker are the presents in?
在我旁边的柜子里  我口袋里有密码  不过你们先
They're in the locker right next to me. The combination is in my pocket, if you'll...
-在他口袋里  -把我放出来啊
- It's in his pocket! - ...just help me out of here.
-拿到了  -来  来
- Got it!  - Okay, come on, come on.
哦  怎么
Oh. Wha...
我们需要两毛五
We need a quarter.
抱歉  我没钱了
Sorry, I'm all out.
为啥不把你其中一张一百块换成两毛五啊
Well, why don't you break one of your hundreds?
我口袋里有两毛五  不过你们先
I have one in my pocket, if you'll just...
-放我出来啊  -他有两毛五
- Let me out of here!  - He has a quarter!
孩子们  小心点儿啊
Kids, be careful!
我觉得这可以算是抢劫了
I think this might qualify as a mugging.
找到了
Found it!
赚到了  耶
Jackpot! Yeah!
我就知道你们能在我的圣诞寻宝中找到了乐趣
I knew you'd have fun on my treasure hunt!
嗯  真是皆大欢喜啊
Well, all's well that ends well.
快把我放出来啊
Get me out of here!
知道吗  现在伯特伦解释了前因后果后
You know, now that Bertram explained everything,
我好像想起来点儿什么东西了
it's all starting to come back to me.
对呀  我也是  但我还是觉得我们忘了什么东西
Yeah, me, too. But I still feel like we're forgetting of something.
在这儿呢
And there it is.
各位  我刚找到了最古怪的东西
Guys, I just found the weirdest thing!
第二古怪的东西
Second weirdest.
转眼间  祖瑞和泰迪
Suddenly, Zuri and Teddy
因为绑架了驯鹿而被通缉就说得通了
being wanted for reindeer-napping makes perfect sense.
什么  这么说是你俩绑走了驯鹿
What, so you two stole the reindeer?
通缉令  驯鹿绑匪
哈  没想到我竟然能说出这样的话
Huh, there's a sentence I never thought I'd say.
我不记得偷走一只驯鹿了
I don't remember stealing a reindeer!
但听起来丹佛人会做出这种事儿嘛
But it sounds like something someone from Denver would do.
-祖瑞  够了  -我们才不会这么做呢
- Zuri, that's enough!  - We don't do that!
没准我们有时会从驯鹿那儿抢点儿小费  不过
Maybe a little innocent reindeer-tipping, now and then, but...
这上说普兰瑟应该在今天公园里的
It says Prancer was supposed to be a part of
音乐会上表演才对
the charity concert in the park today.
你是说  这驯鹿会唱歌吗
You mean, that deer can sing?
哦  你俩就等着牢底坐穿吧
Oh, you two are going away for life!
玩具捐助库
杰茜  为啥我们要去承认这件事啊
Jessie, why do we have to confess?
为啥不能直接放了普兰瑟后开溜呢
Why can't we just release Prancer and run?
对呀  这次我还真赞同她
Yeah, for once, I agree with her.
这真是圣诞奇迹啊
It's a Christmas miracle.
对呀  噢  看看那令人伤感的小围栏啊
Yeah. Aw, look at that sad little pen.
哦  现在我想起来把它牵走的原因了
Oh, now I remember why we took him!
对呀  我也想起来了
Yeah, yeah, me, too!
昨晚在我们找不到你和伯特伦后
After we couldn't find you and Bertram last night,
我们看见普兰瑟关进那牢房里了
we saw Prancer locked up in that prison,
所以我决定把它带回家
so I decided to take him home.
你还竟然同意了
And you went along with that?
我有个艰难的决定
I had a tough choice to make.
要么让我面对一个生气的  哼着鼻子的小怪兽
Either face an angry, snorting beast...
要么面对驯鹿
or the reindeer.
普兰瑟  感谢上苍
Prancer! Thank goodness!
你们在哪找到它的
Where was he?
呃  这事儿够怪的  我们在
Uh, weirdest thing. We found him...
-我们在大楼里找到了它   -在自由女神像那里
- We found him in our building. - In the Statue of Liberty.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你们俩偷走了普兰瑟
You two stole Prancer!
我要去报警了
I'm calling the cops!
好吧  好吧  我们确实偷走了它
Okay, okay! We did it.
但你不会忍心把仨甜美的
But you wouldn't send three sweet,
年轻姑娘关进大牢  对吧
young girls to jail, would you?
呃  不是仨姑娘  我是无辜的
Uh, not three! I'm innocent!
而且她们非常抱歉
And they're really sorry.
道歉不会给孩子们筹款啊
Sorry won't raise money for the kids.
也不能把玩具放到捐助箱啊
Or put toys in their donation bins.
但你现在拿回普兰瑟了
But you've got Prancer back now,
你还可以进行慈善演唱会  对吧
and you're still having the charity concert, right?
错了  普兰瑟失踪后
Wrong! After Prancer went missing,
（注:Joey Fatone是美国歌手兼演员）
我们的歌手  乔伊·法桐  帮忙去找它
our singer, Joey Fatone, helped search for him.
他整晚都在外面  呼唤着普兰瑟的名字
He was out there all night, calling Prancer's name,
等到今儿早时  他失声了
and by this morning, he lost his voice.
还丢了手表  他被抢了
And his watch. He was mugged.
哇  真是坏事连连啊
Wow, way to bring down the room.
她还可以报警啊  别打岔了
She could still call the cops. Dial it back.
现在呢慈善机构找回他们的驯鹿了  但他们没歌手了
So now the charity event has their reindeer back, but they don't have a singer.
祖瑞  我对你失望透顶了
Zuri, I am so disappointed in you.
真不敢相信你偷驯鹿时没叫上我
I can't believe you stole a reindeer without me!
这可在我的遗愿清单上啊
That was on my bucket list!
清单上没我就成了
As long as I'm not on it.
真不敢相信我们离见到乔伊·法桐只差一步之遥了
I can't believe we came so close to meeting the Joey Fatone.
各位  重点是
Guys, the point is,
这活动本来能让很多孩子过一个开心的圣诞节
this event was going to help a lot of kids have a happy Christmas,
但现在这事要泡汤了
and now that's not going to happen.
而且这都是我们的错
And it's all our fault!
我觉得糟透了
I feel terrible.
咱们找不到自己的礼物就已经够苦恼的了
We were so upset when we could not find our presents.
想想看  那些孩子们得不到任何礼物时  他们会咋想
Imagine how these kids will feel when they do not get any.
我们肯定还有方法补救的
There's got to be something we can do.
等等  我刚想到一个最好的法子了
Wait! I just got the greatest idea!
你可以在慈善音乐会上唱歌
You can sing at the charity concert,
这会引来很多人来捐玩具
which will attract a huge crowd of toy-givers,
从而将功补过
thereby saving the day?
其实呢  我想说我们来个糕点义卖
Actually, I was gonna say we do an emergency bake sale,
不过我觉得你的法子好多了
but I like your idea way better!
杰茜  非常感谢你自愿为慈善音乐会唱歌
Jessie, thank you so much for offering to sing for the charity.
你会唱歌  对吧
You can sing, right?
跟小鸟一样甜美
Like a bird.
她比梨树上的山鹑还要可爱呢
And she looks cuter than a partridge in a pear tree!
谢了
Thanks.
我只希望来看的观众不止三个
I just wish we had more than three peeps a watchin'.
对呀  这没有我们预期中的好
Yeah, it's not the turnout we expected,
但至少我们收到个几个玩具啊
but at least we'll get a few toys.
不止几个啊  快看
More than a few! Look.
看看这些礼物啊
Look at all the presents!
杰茜  我们仔细想了想你说的话
Jessie, we thought about what you said,
然后意识到我们
and we realized we've only been thinking
今年圣诞节都太自私了
about ourselves this Christmas.
所以我们想把所有的礼物都捐到玩具捐助库里
So we want to donate all of our presents to the toy drive.
是吗
You do?
你们太贴心了
That is so sweet of you.
我为你们而感到自豪
I am so proud of you guys!
嗯  我们已经拥有很多了
Well, we already have so much.
还有  你知道吗
And, you know what?
不自私的感觉真是太棒了
Not being selfish feels really good.
啊  卢克
Aw, Luke.
哇  看看这些袜子里下面藏了什么
Wow, look what was tucked in with these socks!
亚马逊河游轮之旅加上飞索冒险
An Amazon river cruise and zip-line adventure!
还是以你为荣
Still proud.
大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas,everybody!
请大家热烈欢迎非常有才华的
Please welcome the very talented,
但愿如此吧
hopefully,
杰茜·普利斯科
Jessie Prescott.
即使她唱的很烂  也请大家多捐点玩具  谢谢
Even if she stinks, please donate more toys! Thank you.
Debby Ryan - Favorite Time of Year
需要弄点那槲寄生
<i>Gotta have a little mistletoe</i>
再掺和着一点雪橇铃
<i>Mix it with a little jingle bells</i>
还需要一点冰雪的寒冷
<i>Need to have a bit of winter snow</i>
耶
<i>Yeah</i>
快点来  跟我来庆祝
<i>Come on over, celebrate with me</i>
把天使挂在圣诞树
<i>Hang a seraphon a Christmas tree</i>
把所有的东西系起来
<i>Tie it all up with a perfect bow</i>
你和我
<i>You and I</i>
我们今晚梦多
<i>We'll be dreaming tonight</i>
炉火边
<i>By the fire</i>
我迫不及待  因为这是我
<i>I can't wait 'cause it's my</i>
一年中最喜欢的时候
<i>Favorite time of year</i>
对呀  就快要来喽
<i>Yeah, it's almost here</i>
你看见了吗
<i>Can you see it now?</i>
就要  就要  就要来了
<i>It's coming and coming and coming around</i>
我一年中最喜欢的时候
<i>My favorite time of year</i>
从空气中感受
<i>Feel it in the air</i>
你感觉到了吗
<i>Can you feel it now?</i>
就要  就要  就要来了
<i>It's coming and coming and coming around ♪</i>
谢谢
Thanks.
好吧  出租车在来的路上了
Okay, the cab is on its way.
嗯  拜拜啦
Mmm, bye-bye.
提醒一下  在这里帮助人是要付小费的
Just so you know, it is customary to tip the help.
他啥时候帮过我们啦
When did he help us?
你能把这两毛五找零吗
Can you break a quarter?
杰茜  再次感谢你让我们度过了个难以忘怀的圣诞节
Jessie, thanks again, for giving us a Christmas we'll never forget.
虽然我们还没完全记起来过
And still don't completely remember.
我只希望我能晓得昨晚做的是啥实验
I just wish I knew what experiment I was attempting last night
把我们都弄昏迷  并且让我们失去短期记忆了
that rendered us unconscious and erased our short-term memory.
各位  快来看啊
Guys, check this out.
貌似我找到可以解释前因后果的东西了
I think I just found something that will explain everything!
查莉  如果你找到这段录像并且在想我在干啥的话
Charlie, if you find this and you wonder what happened to me,
我会跟你说  你姐被驯鹿碾过去了
your sister got run over by a reindeer!
普兰瑟  你就要到调皮名单上了
Prancer, you are about to go on the naughty list!
哇哦
Whoa!
哇哦  哇哦  哇哦
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
现在我知道为啥圣诞老人把它们留在屋顶上了
Now I know why Santa leaves them on the roof.
拉维  那个昏迷血清在哪儿呢
Ravi! Where's that knock-out serum?
我们要让这驯鹿冷静下来  快点
We need to tranquilize this reindeer, stat!
就快好了  卢克  把淡黄绿色的药品加进去
Almost there! Luke, add the chartreuse chemical!
我不知道淡黄绿色是啥啊
I don't know what chartreuse is!
呃  来  试试这个
Uh, here! Let's use this!
不  那是青绿色  你这二百五
No! That is turquoise, you idiot!
你就不能只有红蓝绿黄这些颜色的液体吗
You couldn't just have red, blue, green, and yellow?
啊哦  你把昏迷血清弄成气体了
Uh-oh! You have turned the knock-out serum into a vapor,
我们都会昏迷过去的
which could knock us out!
快躲啊  昏迷气体暴走了
Hide! Knock-out vapor on the loose!
这是不是你放臭屁的一种高雅的说法啊
Is that a fancy way of saying you cut the cheese?
哇哦  你吃了啥呀
Whoa, what did you eat?
不能  睡觉
Can't... Sleep.
必须把伯特伦从柜子里放出来
Must get Bertram out of locker.
祝我们好运吧  小查莉
Wish us good luck, Charlie.
好吧  这确实解释了这事儿的来龙去脉
Okay, that does explain everything.
只是  查莉是何许人也
Except, who the heck's Charlie?
需要弄点那槲寄生
<i>Gotta have a little mistletoe</i>
再掺和着一点雪橇铃
<i>Mix it with a little jingle bells</i>
还需要一点冰雪的寒冷
<i>Need to have a bit of winter snow</i>
因为这是我
<i>'Cause it's my</i>
一年中最喜欢的时候
<i>Favorite time of year</i>
对呀  就快要来喽
<i>Yeah, it's almost here</i>
你看见了吗
<i>Can you see it now?</i>
就要  就要  就要来了
<i>It's coming and coming and coming around</i>